<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Amanda Nicosia</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amandanicosia.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amandanicosia.com/</link>
	<description>Content Writer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 07:01:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://amandanicosia.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-Black-and-White-Circle-Personal-Logo-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Amanda Nicosia</title>
	<link>https://amandanicosia.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Smart Predictors for Success</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/smart-predictors-for-success/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As marketing professionals, when our clients succeed,&#160;we&#160;succeed. However, with so many variables at play, new clients may question whether or not a marketing strategy will work for them. Assuring clients that customized strategies and best practices are valuable can support claims, but ultimately, results sell. &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/smart-predictors-for-success/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Smart Predictors for Success</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1079" class="elementor elementor-1079">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-302e258e elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="302e258e" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-63a1133e" data-id="63a1133e" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-193d45bf elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="193d45bf" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							
<p>As marketing professionals, when our clients succeed, <em>we</em> succeed. However, with so many variables at play, new clients may question whether or not a marketing strategy will work for them. Assuring clients that customized strategies and best practices are valuable can support claims, but ultimately, results sell.</p>



<p>The great thing about content marketing is that no matter how your strategy is performing, it’s easy to make adjustments based on data and reports to learn what tactics work &#8212; and what needs work. </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s look at a few ways to predict and ensure marketing success for fantastic results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Measure Everything</h2>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://test.local/6-marketing-metrics-that-matter/" target="_blank">Measuring data and metrics</a> may be the most important method for predicting effective marketing.  Knowing where you stand will save you time and money &#8212; if you’re performing well, your data will show it.</p>



<p>Digital marketing makes this especially easy. Measuring message performance allows you to modify your strategy with your overall goals in mind. Basing your decisions on data and feedback will help you invest in the right channels and campaigns for your target personas.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Be Willing to Adapt</h2>



<p>Marketing never slows down. New media, tactics, and trends occur daily in content marketing, <a href="http://test.local/9-ways-to-increase-social-media-engagement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">social media</a>, campaign development, and design. As these evolve, you must be open to shifting your strategy and goals.</p>



<p>Your marketing should be done with purpose. Find out what your clients need and don’t be afraid to try new things. Testing and adjusting your strategy are necessary for success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Go Evergreen</h2>



<p>It&#8217;s likely that much of your previous content is still relevant. <a href="http://test.local/creating-vs-curating-your-social-media-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Repurposing content</a> into new resources can save you time and money. By optimizing for SEO, you also earn a new chance for your thought leadership and materials to be found a second time around.</p>



<p>For every content piece you develop, there should be at least three supplementary pieces of waterfall content. If you write an eBook, create a blog or an infographic around it. This ensures you’re getting the full value out of your valuable content.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>Marketers who adapt to what clients want at <a href="http://test.local/6-types-of-video-marketing-across-the-buyers-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">each stage of the buyer&#8217;s journey</a> are more likely to earn business and trust, so always make adjustments with your clients in mind. </p>



<p>By monitoring your data, listening to clients, and shifting your strategy as needed, you&#8217;ll consistently improve your tactics to produce brilliant results.</p>



<p>Have questions? <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://test.local/contact/" target="_blank">Reach out</a>, happy to help!</p>
						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Break These 5 Social Media Bad Habits</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/break-these-5-social-media-bad-habits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not showing any signs of slowing down, few other marketing channels experience the resilience of social media. Depending on your goals and target audience, there&#8217;s at least one ideal social media platform that will amplify your brand&#8217;s strategy and results. As these platforms evolve, so &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/break-these-5-social-media-bad-habits/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Break These 5 Social Media Bad Habits</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not showing any signs of slowing down, few other marketing channels experience the resilience of social media. Depending on your goals and target audience, there&#8217;s at least one ideal social media platform that will amplify your brand&#8217;s strategy and results.</p>



<p>As these platforms evolve, so should your social media marketing habits. If you haven’t seen much growth from your social channels , maybe it’s time to reconsider your strategies. Are you tracking the right metrics? Have they led to concrete results?</p>



<p>If your social media routine could use some reworking, this blog examines some social media bad habits &#8212; and how to break them for good.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Hard Sell</h2>



<p>Far too often, brands lay it on thick. Generally, customers are put off by hard-sell statements because people use social media primarily to learn and socialize. By demonstrating how your products or services have helped others, your benefits will speak louder than an overt pitch.</p>



<p>Additionally, hard sales campaigns don’t give your audience the chance to get to know your brand at a human level, nor will they develop trust or loyalty for it. Instead, reach out to your followers personally &#8212; social success comes from real communication.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Talk Less, Listen More</h2>



<p>Social conversations are a two-way street. Be sure you’re remaining attentive and engaging by setting up social listening to monitor brand mentions and to get involved in the discussion. Doing so increases brand awareness. The most memorable social campaigns showcase great responses from the brand.</p>



<p>Even negative comments, while not always salvageable, can be an opportunity to listen and learn. Responding promptly will show the public that you care about your customers and stand by your brand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Using Vanity Metrics</h2>



<p>While brand image and customer engagement are positive for your business, vanity metrics don’t typically demonstrate real growth.</p>



<p>Focusing on metrics and KPIs that measure conversions will provide better insight for your business goals. Awareness and impressions are important, but by measuring the right data, your social efforts will provide tangible results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Spread Too Thin</h2>



<p>Some social platforms work better than others. By trying to be successful on every platform, you’ll likely be investing too much time and money into the wrong networks.</p>



<p>Instead, find out which social media channels benefit&nbsp;<em>your&nbsp;</em>brand. Examine the platforms that attract real leads and focus those to better allocate marketing efforts and efficiently invest your time and budget.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Scheduling Fails</h2>



<p>Many companies post on social without structure or strategy, but without a consistent schedule, your posts may go unseen.</p>



<p>If you use an automated scheduling tool, make sure you’re posting &#8220;like a human.&#8221; If your posts are published at the same time daily, or if there are errors that go unnoticed because you’re relying too heavily on automation, your audience will notice. Vary your calendar and add timely, relevant content to your schedule to start a conversation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>As social media continues to evolve, so will your routine. Learn what&#8217;s beneficial for your brand and develop a strategy that aligns your social habits with your business goals.</p>



<p>Thanks for reading and<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://amandanicosia.com/contact/" target="_blank"> let me know</a> if you have any questions!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Choosing a Web Designer</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/choosing-a-web-designer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your website communicates with customers 24/7 and is often the only way they’ll reach out to your company. This means your website plays many roles, from salesman to thought leader, and must reflect your brand values, build relationships, and produce results. A good website should highlight the &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/choosing-a-web-designer/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Choosing a Web Designer</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Your website communicates with customers 24/7 and is often the <em>only </em>way they’ll reach out to your company. This means your website plays many roles, from salesman to thought leader, and must reflect your brand values, build relationships, and produce results.</p>



<p>A good website should highlight the following features:</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Easy accessibility</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Seamless user experience</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Intuitive design</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Positive engagement</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Valuable results</p>



<p>Choosing a web developer to manage your site takes careful consideration, as unexpected issues during development can change the project scope, timeline, and budget. Fortunately, the right research and preparation can go a long way.</p>



<p>Finding the ideal web developer for you company means asking key, critical questions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Do they understand your goals?</h2>



<p>Your website illustrates your company’s mission and vision. As an extension of your brand, your site must support your organization&#8217;s values and goals, including:</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Building brand awareness, value, and trust</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Generating and nurturing new leads</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Attracting prospects and maintaining relationships</p>



<p>A good web development firm maintains your brand identity and target objectives and should recognize deficits as well as opportunities for growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can they achieve your goals?</h2>



<p>Your web developer should have the right skills to meet and exceed your goals. How does your potential designer rate in the following areas?</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Digital marketing strategies</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Design, automation, and user experience</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Analytics, SEO, and reporting</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CMS and CRM</p>



<p>Communication can make or break your partnership &#8212; clarify expectations around budget and timeline and try not to cut corners when investing in your website. Your developer should provide an initial proposal that accounts for proofs, tweaks, and unexpected setbacks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Are they in it for the long haul?</h2>



<p>Another major consideration is if the agency will support your website after launch. New websites involve bug fixes and maintenance, often requiring an expert. A company that supports their design and stands by their work is an ideal long-term partner.</p>



<p>Aside from routine maintenance, a reputable web partner will make sure their work provides results, not just good looks. Ensure they provide tracking tools for performance, lead generation, and conversions to help you measure metrics, ROI, and engagement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>When i&#8217;s time to choose, remember that the right designer will deliver the best in both design&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;functionality without too much compromise.</p>



<p>Be sure they are dedicated to your goals and have qualifying experience. By communicating and understanding overall expectations, your partnership will be positive and mutually beneficial. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Metrics That Matter</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/6-marketing-metrics-that-matter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Few career paths blend logic and art as seamlessly as marketing, where right-brain creativity meets left-brain analytics to achieve a comprehensive spectrum of creative content and smarter SMART goals. Once this scale has been established, marketing professionals are expected to prove that their campaigns are generating &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/6-marketing-metrics-that-matter/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Marketing Metrics That Matter</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1070" class="elementor elementor-1070">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-737cd662 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="737cd662" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-2889fcb4" data-id="2889fcb4" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-1f228f55 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="1f228f55" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							
<p>Few career paths blend logic and art as seamlessly as marketing, where right-brain creativity meets left-brain analytics to achieve a comprehensive spectrum of creative content and smarter SMART goals.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Once this scale has been established, marketing professionals are expected to prove that their campaigns <a href="http://test.local/smart-predictors-for-success/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">are generating real results</a>. This means figuring out which metrics are valuable to your campaigns and worth tracking.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Understanding what to measure and why is the first step to content marketing success. Here are some metrics and KPIs that serve as smart indicators of effective marketing.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Customer Acquisition Cost (CAC)</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>The customer acquisition cost (CAC) averages what your company spends to acquire a new customer. It’s also the cost of convincing a prospect to select your brand.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Knowing how much you’re spending on each customer helps you invest in the right channels and avoid the ones that aren’t worth your time. The lower your CAC, the higher your profit.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Quick Math: </strong>Sales and Marketing Cost ÷ New Customers</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Marketing’s Percentage of CAC</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>This percentage measures the marketing portion of your CAC. New customers are often found through promotional campaigns, so isolating marketing’s impact shows you how your team is performing.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Long term, this lets you know if your budget is being allocated more toward sales or marketing. An increase may mean marketing costs went up, while a decrease could mean higher sales spending. Again, the lower is better.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Quick Math: </strong>Marketing Cost ÷ Total Sales and Marketing Cost</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ratio of Customer Lifetime Value to CAC</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>This ratio estimates how much your company gains per customer compared to how much you spent to find them.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Especially useful for subscription-based brands, the longer a customer relationship, the more value they offer. This metric should amount to at least three times more return than what it cost to initially obtain the customer.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Quick Math: </strong>Ratio of LTV:CAC</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Time to Payback CAC</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>This metric demonstrates how many months it takes for your company to reach a break-even point from what it spent on CAC.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>The less time it takes, the faster you’ll start profiting from each new customer. Earlier is better, but companies typically expect to see a return within a year.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Quick Math:</strong> CAC ÷ Margin Adjusted Revenue</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Marketing Influenced Customer Percentage</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Your marketing team nurtures leads long before the sale, and now you have a metric to show it. This metric measures marketing’s influence on leads throughout the buyer’s journey.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Relationship building, lead generation, and sales support are all backed by this metric. It’s perfect for giving your CEO a big-picture understanding of marketing’s impact on the sales process.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Quick Math: </strong>Total New Customers Linked to Marketing ÷ Total New Customers</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ready to Report</h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Presenting marketing metrics that speak to management will help you make a case for budget increases and new marketing initiatives. Being able to prove your results can benefit your entire team both now and into the future.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Not the greatest at math? <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://test.local/contact/" target="_blank">Feel free to reach out</a>!</p>
<p></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Plan Your Trade Show Marketing</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/how-to-plan-your-trade-show-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exhibiting at trade shows is an exciting&#160;part of your marketing strategy. Trade shows allow you to connect with your customers in person, leading to opportunities for building relationships and showcasing your products. But trade show marketing takes more than your sales team occupying a booth &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/how-to-plan-your-trade-show-marketing/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Plan Your Trade Show Marketing</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Exhibiting at trade shows is an exciting&nbsp;part of your marketing strategy. Trade shows allow you to connect with your customers in person, leading to opportunities for building relationships and showcasing your products.</p>



<p>But trade show marketing takes more than your sales team occupying a booth and hoping for the best. Attracting visitors to your exhibit starts well before the show and is just as important as following up with your contacts after it&#8217;s ended.</p>



<p>Trade show marketing takes careful planning and strategy to engage visitors and hold their interest. Here are some steps for effective trade show marketing to ensure you make the most out of exhibiting.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Planning Ahead</h2>



<p>Trade show planning begins months prior to the show. The first step is determining your lead goals. Decide who you&#8217;ll reach out to and how you’ll interact with visitors at the show. Keep in mind what actions you&#8217;d like them to take, such as scheduling meetings or email registration.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Before the Show</h2>



<p>Begin by encouraging registered attendees to visit your booth. Often, you can purchase a contact list from organizers, but always be sure to verify it’s from a valid source. </p>



<p>Your content should broadcast your attendance, offer sponsorship opportunities, or invite partnerships with organizers. Reach out to previous attendees, pre-registered guests, and your own current customers for the highest engagement.</p>



<p>Next, design a landing page on your website customized for the show. Share your booth number, any special demonstrations, and one-on-one meeting offers. You can also provide some insight for improving attendee experience in exchange for contact information.</p>



<p>Trade show focused content like blogs or video also help draw a crowd. These add personality and are easy to share on your site and social channels. Your content should focus on industry topics and answer attendee questions, but ultimately will promote your exhibit at the show.</p>



<p>Engaging in email marketing is another great way to make your mark. Spread the word and share content through email and social media marketing. Segment your contacts and send relevant information focused on specific industries. </p>



<p>Through your social channels, you can build excitement and awareness by letting your followers know what to expect at the show. Paid ad campaigns and geo-targeting let you target specific companies that will benefit from your marketing and exhibiting.</p>



<p>Finally, include assets in your booth design that you&#8217;ve found helpful. If videos entertained prospects online, they’ll likely enjoy them at your booth during the trade show.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">During the Show</h2>



<p>Give attendees a reason to stop by your booth. Swag and branded items are fun, but make sure you focus on your target audience by offering exclusive promotions. Product showcases, live podcasts, and other demonstrations will draw in the right prospects.</p>



<p>Having a tablet or device set up in your booth or in the hands of your sales reps is a must for lead capture. Attendees can scan their badge for instant sign up, emails, and offers. They can also be directed to a landing page full of valuable information, memorable content, and contact details.</p>



<p>The staff at your booth should be knowledgeable and personable when interacting with prospects. Train the team so that they fully understand the expectations of the marketing strategy.</p>



<p>Throughout the show, share live activity on social media, including videos, photos, contests, or sign-up promotions. Encourage followers to share or tag for more social engagement. Your audience will enjoy following along and being included in the action.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">After the Show</h2>



<p>Great planning paves the way for positive post-show reviews. Work with your sales team to figure out how you’ll connect with attendees after the show. Organize your contacts, generate workflows, and reach out directly to high-potential prospects.</p>



<p>A nurture strategy is also ideal at this point. You can share what you learned at the show and offer insights to your visitors. Track and analyze your follow-up performance; the better your segmentation, the easier it will be to measure success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A Great Investment</h2>



<p>Having an organized approach means a greater return on investment and will yield a better overall experience. Review your strategy to see what has worked, what you&#8217;d like to try, and how you can improve your trade show marketing for future exhibits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating vs. Curating Your Social Media Content</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/creating-vs-curating-your-social-media-content/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Content marketing and social media go hand-in-hand, but managing your organization’s social media schedule is no easy task. Planning a steady content schedule may be met with hefty roadblocks like juggling multiple tasks, time and budget constraints, and creative staff shortages. Although writing content regularly &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/creating-vs-curating-your-social-media-content/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Creating vs. Curating Your Social Media Content</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1061" class="elementor elementor-1061">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-69dffd09 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="69dffd09" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-440e4746" data-id="440e4746" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-28a2bd1b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="28a2bd1b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							
<p>Content marketing and social media go hand-in-hand, but managing your organization’s social media schedule is no easy task. Planning a steady content schedule may be met with hefty roadblocks like juggling multiple tasks, time and budget constraints, and creative staff shortages.</p>



<p>Although writing content regularly on top of your other responsibilities can be challenging, it&#8217;s important to mix it up. Many organizations use content curation in addition to content creation, resulting in better social media consistency, thought leadership, and engagement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Create and Curate</h2>



<p>Where created content is developed from scratch, curated content is shared from reliable third-party sources. Both are used in tandem to provide relevant industry information to your followers.</p>



<p>As a recent social media tactic, there are still stigmas associated with curating content. Fears around sharing competitor content, appearing apathetic, or losing business have led many organizations to doubt its worth. However, there are plenty of benefits and advantages in combining both of these methods into your social strategy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Created Content: The Foundation of Your Strategy</h2>



<p>Developing content should be at the center of your content strategy. Articles, blogs, white papers, infographics, or eBooks made by your company all work to lay out a strong foundation for your digital marketing plan.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Thought Leadership</strong></h3>



<p>Original content positions your brand as an industry expert. As a thought leader, you offer fresh insight, knowledge, and influence. Your customers are seeking relevant information for making a purchase and your content will more than likely influence their final decision.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Driving Conversions</strong></h3>



<p>Created content drives traffic to your website and improves conversions. Having a clear call to action speaks volumes, especially for product launches, events, or announcements &#8212; news travels quickly on social media.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Brand Differentiation</strong></h3>



<p>Your owned content also distinguishes you from competitors. A distinct voice highlights your brand and creates a niche for your business. Additionally, if your competitors leave content creation out of their social strategy, you already have an advantage.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Curated Content: A Wealth of Information</h2>



<p>The basis of social media is to socialize, share, and promote ideas, but don’t limit your posts to personal promotion only. Having a broadcast mentality may negatively impact your brand as followers expect a variety of content to learn from.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Resource Saving</strong></h3>



<p>According to Content Marketing Institute, <a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2015/09/b2b-content-marketing-research/">76% of marketers</a> make it their goal to produce more content, but ambition like this comes with time and budget demands.</p>



<p>Luckily, curated content saves you both. Curating lets you share content quickly to help remain on schedule while being inexpensive to maintain.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Create Opportunities</strong></h3>



<p>Sharing content improves audience interaction and offers new engagement opportunities. The more you connect, the better your lead nurturing. Curated content also gets higher click rates, receiving <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.convinceandconvert.com/social-media-measurement/new-research-finds-the-curation-vs-creation-sweet-spot/" target="_blank">33% more clicks</a> than owned content.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Diverse Viewpoints</strong></h3>



<p>Curating content gives your audience more perspective. Through curated content, you can increase viewership and become an industry advisor, offering new insight on common topics. Add social captions and annotations of your own for brand influence and visibility.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dynamic Duo</h2>



<p>Content creation and curation complement one another, blending into a cohesive strategy. Using each will help you set a consistent posting schedule and align your content goals.</p>



<p>Set a realistic target; try sharing content that is 40% created and 60% curated. Be sure your curated posts complement the content you already create and publish across a variety of channels to get the most out of your content.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>Combining these valuable content tactics will help you create a consistent social strategy that fits your brand, yielding remarkable content marketing success.</p>



<p>Ready to add some variety to your strategy? <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://test.local/contact/" target="_blank">Contact me</a> with any questions.</p>
						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Types of Video Marketing Across the Buyer&#8217;s Journey</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/6-types-of-video-marketing-across-the-buyers-journey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From high-production commercials to vibrant social media ads, video has always been an important staple of advertising. Video is convenient and shareable, making it an ideal medium for marketing. Producing video has also become easier and more cost-effective.  But before you jump into a video-first strategy, you’ll want &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/6-types-of-video-marketing-across-the-buyers-journey/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">6 Types of Video Marketing Across the Buyer&#8217;s Journey</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>From high-production commercials to vibrant social media ads, video has always been an important staple of advertising. Video is convenient and shareable, making it an ideal medium for marketing. Producing video has also become easier and more cost-effective. </p>



<p>But before you jump into a video-first strategy, you’ll want to be sure your viewers are discovering the right content for where they stand in their buyer’s journey.</p>



<p>During each stage, your buyers are seeking different information that might be irrelevant at other stages. For instance, customers who are ready to make a purchase in the decision stage probably won&#8217;t need an introductory how-to video for those in the awareness stage. </p>



<p>Targeting videos for every stage offers content customized for your prospect, guiding them through their buyer’s journey. The right video marketing educates and encourages a purchase decision.</p>



<p>When creating a video strategy, ask yourself: What problems can this solve? What are the challenges your viewer is likely facing? Which stage are they currently in?</p>



<p>With these in mind, you can select the right video types to guide your audience from search to sale. Targeted videos provide more opportunities to simplify a user&#8217;s experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Awareness Stage: Top of Funnel</h2>



<p>In the awareness stage, your prospects know they have a problem and are now conducting research. Top-of-funnel video marketing means introducing new concepts and offering solutions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Explainer Videos</strong></h3>



<p>Right now, your prospects are seeking new information. With an explainer video, you can clarify a difficult topic or explain a resourceful approach. Explainer videos are also useful for improving your SEO and audience reach.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Thought Leadership Videos</strong></h3>



<p>Through thought leadership videos, you can position yourself as a trusted front-runner in your field. Thought leadership videos promote your industry knowledge and expertise for your brand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Consideration Stage: Middle of Funnel</h2>



<p>Your customers have done their research and are now weighing potential solutions. Success in the consideration stage depends on brand recognition and engaging with prospects who have questions you can answer.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Commercials</strong></h3>



<p>Commercials introduce your brand and values to prospects. Outline a problem and the solutions that differentiate your brand from competitors. Creative visuals, inspiring narratives, and unique storytelling all lead to memorable commercials and more engagement.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Corporate Culture Videos</strong></h3>



<p>Show off your company’s character and add some personality with a company culture video. What sets your organization apart from the rest? What makes it an awesome place to work? A friendly atmosphere speaks volumes and can make a great first impression.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Decision Stage: Bottom of Funnel</h2>



<p>The bottom of the funnel is your moment to shine. At this decision stage, you want to convince potential buyers beyond a doubt that you&#8217;ll solve their issues. This is where they should immediately associate their desired solutions with your brand.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Testimonial Videos</strong></h3>



<p>Combining the best of both worlds, testimonial videos highlight both the benefits&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;features of your company’s product or service. Testimonial videos build your brand’s credibility while showing off your product&#8217;s impressive features.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Instructional &amp; Product Demos</strong></h3>



<p>Demonstration videos assure customers that you stand by your product, even after they&#8217;ve made their purchase. Demonstration videos may help customers assemble their new product or provide helpful ways to care for their investment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Looking Beyond the Funnel</h2>



<p>Most importantly, show customers your appreciation for their business. Send them a personalized thank you video or personalized content. They&#8217;ll appreciate the courtesy and likely will consider your brand in the future.</p>



<p>No matter what stage your prospects are in, video marketing is a great addition to your marketing strategy. Using dedicated content for buyers at each stage will encourage brand loyalty and growth. The more you engage with your prospects, the easier it will be to guide them to a final purchase decision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 Ways to Increase Social Media Engagement</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/9-ways-to-increase-social-media-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 07:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social media has captivated society. In a short time, it&#8217;s changed how we connect one-on-one and universally, becoming an integral part of our communication. Try as we might, it’s hard to imagine life without it. Platforms have gone through various updates and versions, but social &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/9-ways-to-increase-social-media-engagement/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">9 Ways to Increase Social Media Engagement</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Social media has captivated society. In a short time, it&#8217;s changed how we connect one-on-one and universally, becoming an integral part of our communication. Try as we might, it’s hard to imagine life without it.</p>



<p>Platforms have gone through various updates and versions, but social media maintains the same goal: meeting the user’s needs. The same is true for social media marketing; it’s only as useful as your customer engagement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Importance of Social Media Interaction</h2>



<p>With more brands joining in on the action, competition for consumer response is fierce. Modern digital strategies like paid ads and videos add flair and interest, but with countless companies vying for attention, consumers have become distracted and selective when deciding which brands to follow and trust. </p>



<p>Modern marketers must align their social strategies for more interaction. Since social media leads online communication, connecting with your audience across all channels is key. Consider the opportunities (and limitations) of each to build your social media performance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Amplifying Your Social Media Engagement</h2>



<p>Generally, higher social media engagement can support your brand in three areas:</p>



<ul><li>Strengthen brand-client relationships</li><li>Build trust and customer loyalty</li><li>Improve your sales and recommendations</li></ul>



<p>To help you improve your social engagement, it’s important to understand the methods behind developing smart social media habits. From setting goals to identifying your audience, amplifying your social media engagement increases brand value and results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1) Get Out Your Toolbox</h2>



<p>Creating social media posts is easier when you have the right assets. Whether it’s checking grammar or social monitoring, a full set of resourceful tools, apps, and plugins can simplify your process. Here are a few to help you get started:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.hubspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HubSpot</a>: Schedule posts, monitor mentions, and track your efforts.</li><li><a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Canva</a>: Design visual posts from templates for all your platforms.</li><li><a href="https://www.pexels.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pexels</a>: Download free, high-quality stock photos to use in your posts.</li><li><a href="https://www.grammarly.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Grammarly</a>: Proof your copy and grammar with this browser extension.</li><li><a href="https://moz.com/tools/fresh-web-explorer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Moz Fresh Web Explorer</a>: Find brand mentions, competitors, and keywords.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2) Determine Your Audience</h2>



<p>Deciding who you are directing your content toward will help you customize the message and tone of your social media posts. To select an audience, first get to know your customers. Identify your buyer personas to learn more about them and social media campaigns that will interest them.</p>



<p>When considering your ideal customers, keep these questions in mind:</p>



<ul><li>What are their biggest problems?</li><li>What do they use social media for?</li><li>What commonly unites your customers?</li><li>Where do they get their news and trends?</li><li>Who do they follow on social media?</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3) Map Your Goals</h2>



<p>Post with purpose. Every time you publish, keep your core values in mind. What do you want to achieve through social posting? Take a look at these memorable ways to set social media goals:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">80/20 Rule – When planning your content:</h3>



<ul><li>80% of your posts should educate and entertain your audience.</li><li>20% of your posts should promote your own brand or business.</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">10:4:1 Rule – For every 15 posts you create:</h3>



<ul><li>10 posts should link to third-party content.</li><li>4 posts can link to your company’s blog.</li><li>1 post links to a landing page or sales offer.</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SMART Goals – Develop your goals to be:</h3>



<ul><li>Specific: Select precise targets to focus on and improve.</li><li>Measurable: Metrics should be easily quantifiable.</li><li>Attainable: Pick realistic benchmarks and grow from there.</li><li>Relevant: Objectives should relate to your company or industry.</li><li>Time-bound: Deadlines set parameters and drive progress.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4) Understand Your Platforms</h2>



<p>Connecting with your audience varies by social network. It’s your job to decide which ones are best for you. All social channels share common elements like text, images, and links, but even these serve different purposes for each network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here are some examples of how to use each platform:</p>



<ul><li>Facebook: Share image and video content to inform and engage. Avoid being pushy with promotion; the focus here is on content-driven activity.</li><li>Twitter: Keep text to a minimum and speak casually, but feel free to post several times a day. And don’t be shy with hashtags—they started on Twitter! #TweetTips</li><li>LinkedIn: Network and connect with industry professionals through your business, groups, events, and posts. Brands can also be more direct and promotional here.</li><li>Instagram: Get your camera and enhance your brand image, literally. Share bold pictures and videos with fun filters. Get creative with app features.</li><li>YouTube: Branded links and detailed descriptions play a big role in how your audience finds your content. Encourage subscribing to stay connected with your viewers.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5) Generate Links</h2>



<p>Social media is a great way to guide your audience to your resources, like your website, blog, and promotions. But without a link, your audience never leaves the social platform.</p>



<p>To encourage more interaction, include links and manage them.</p>



<ul><li>Check that your links lead to the right destinations.</li><li>Correct, remove, or redirect broken links.</li><li>Try original URLs or a&nbsp;<a href="https://bitly.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">link shortener</a>&nbsp;for lengthy URLS.</li><li>Recheck links often to ensure they land on the right pages.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">6) Create a Story</h2>



<p>Authentic storytelling creates brand value on social media. You won&#8217;t get far with generic offers like “big sale!” Are you interested in posts like that, or do you scroll past them? Your audience is human; they want to connect on a personal level.</p>



<p>Use appealing dialogue and brand messaging with character. Your social posts may be your consumers&#8217; first impression of your company, so exhibit some personality up front. Remarkable storytelling includes:</p>



<ul><li>Speaking directly to your audience.</li><li>Being consistent across channels.</li><li>Relevant narratives and metaphors.</li><li>Connecting through sensory descriptions.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">7) Apply Call to Action Links</h2>



<p>A call to action (CTA) link directs your audience to the content they’re looking for. It can be straightforward or catchy, as long as it isn&#8217;t too long and gets the point across.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Including a branded CTA link assures your viewer they&#8217;re landing on a trustworthy page, like your website or landing offer. According to Rebrandly, branded call to action links provide trust to your consumers,&nbsp;<a href="https://support.rebrandly.com/hc/en-us/articles/115007615288-Generic-short-URLs-vs-branded-links-which-has-a-better-CTR-" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increasing click through rates for your posts by 39%</a>.</p>



<p>For flawless CTA links, try these tips:</p>



<ul><li>Use clear, simple language.</li><li>Keep it short but stand out.</li><li>Place CTAs at the end of your post.</li><li>Monitor CTA links for functionality.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">8) Make Your Posts Pop</h2>



<p>According to HubSpot,&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/visual-content-marketing-strategy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">engagement is boosted by over 300%</a>&nbsp;when both text and graphics are included in a post. Imagery captures attention and leads to better interaction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not exactly a graphic design pro? No problem. There are tons of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online template tools</a>&nbsp;you can use to get started. When uploading images to social media, keep in mind:</p>



<ul><li>Each platform has different guidelines for image dimensions.</li><li>Sizing standards change periodically so be sure to stay current.</li><li>Review&nbsp;<a href="https://sproutsocial.com/insights/social-media-image-sizes-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">up-to-date guides</a>&nbsp;for the latest social media image dimensions.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">9) Hash It Out</h2>



<p>Hashtags help summarize and highlight your posts. You can follow popular topics or trends, join in on conversations, and be found by more viewers. Some platforms encourage going hashtag crazy, while others advise using them sparingly.</p>



<p>Including the right hashtags means your posts are more likely to be seen. This increases your chances for engagement where you otherwise may not have been found. Hashtags help you:</p>



<ul><li>Build your brand</li><li>Increase interactivity</li><li>Discover new audiences</li><li>See what’s trending</li><li>Find your niche</li></ul>



<p>Try several techniques and see what performs well for your brand. For a complete overview on creating hashtags for each platform, check out Hootsuite&#8217;s guide&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.hootsuite.com/how-to-use-hashtags/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Use Hashtags</a>.</p>



<p>Ultimately, social media marketing exists to humanize your brand. The best ways to boost post engagement revolve around being consistent, telling a story, and interacting with your audience. Practice some of these strategies to see what works best for you and remember that social media is all about developing human connections.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Things Customer-Centric Brands Should Know</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/what-customer-centric-brands-should-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 06:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, an established client decided it was time for a rebrand. Their main goal was to implement customer-first messaging, focused on positive impacts for the buyer instead of product features. Rewriting your copy may not seem monumental, but it represents a shift in the B2B &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/what-customer-centric-brands-should-know/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">5 Things Customer-Centric Brands Should Know</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recently, an established client decided it was time for a rebrand. Their main goal was to implement customer-first messaging, focused on positive impacts for the buyer instead of product features.</p>



<p>Rewriting your copy may not seem monumental, but it represents a shift in the B2B industry. Brands are realizing that going the extra mile to please customers leaves a lasting impression.</p>



<p>Customer-centric marketing focuses on customer experience throughout the sales process, creating long-term relationships while driving customer loyalty and repeat business. By prioritizing buyer success through customer-centric marketing, you can create value as a recognizable and reliable brand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Industry Is Shifting</strong></h2>



<p>The concept of customer-centric marketing gained attention when customers started taking the buyer’s journey into their own hands. Ecommerce and online storefronts have made it easy for customers to find what they want, when they want it. Transactions are completed online without the buyer ever contacting the seller.</p>



<p>For a long time, only sellers handled product information. They&#8217;d limit access to these resources, requiring customers to reach out directly. This was clearly advantageous to sellers, but inconvenient for buyers, especially if they wanted to do any research on their own.</p>



<p>In a digitally motivated age, it’s no surprise that the B2B marketplace has changed. Buyers don&#8217;t need to wait for product information; ecommerce websites and online channels display the information in real time. Ultimately, the buyer is in control.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Competition Is Rising</strong></h2>



<p>With digital channels on the rise, competition is growing. Industrial engineers and technical professionals can access more resources than in the past, making it difficult to stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>This creates a challenge for brand diversity based solely on product quality. No longer do claims like “Top-Notch Service!” or “Best in the Business!” work when other brands are repeating the same thing. Customers know better and are already tuning you out.</p>



<p>Instead, observe their motivations and address their concerns. What questions are they asking? What sets you apart from the competition? What problems can you solve?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Methods Are Reforming</strong></h2>



<p>Customers favor simplicity &#8212; It’s in our nature to seek ways to solve problems, improve our routines, and develop solutions that make life easier. In order for your brand to succeed, you must offer tangible convenience that your customers cannot find elsewhere.</p>



<p>As brands update their strategies, it&#8217;s the customer’s job to control the buying process and the brand’s job to deliver an excellent experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Companies Are Changing</strong></h2>



<p>Customer-centric organizations are seeing huge growth, achieving <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/ie/Documents/Strategy/2014_customer_centricity_deloitte_ireland.pdf" target="_blank">60% more profitability</a> than those who haven’t employed a focus on the customer as a strategy.</p>



<p>But becoming a customer-centric brand must become a core value for your entire company. A customer-centric brand shares the client’s voice through team collaboration across all channels and experiences. Therefore, everyone needs to be onboard.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Customer Needs Are Evolving</strong></h2>



<p>Customer centricity can be summarized simply as listening to your customers, understanding their needs, and planning effective solutions</p>



<p>Great customer service must be tailored to each client, going beyond asking questions to anticipating their challenges ahead of time. Delivering solutions before they knew they were even looking showcases an outstanding customer-focused strategy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>



<p>Becoming a customer-centric brand means recognizing the true value of customer happiness. Understanding their challenges allows you to provide the right solutions that align your goals with theirs.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking for more ways to focus on your customers, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://amandanicosia.com/contact/" target="_blank">free to reach out</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Tips for Better B2B Content Marketing</title>
		<link>https://amandanicosia.com/5-tips-for-better-b2b-content-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Nicosia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 06:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandanicosia.com/?p=1037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Content marketing is paving the way for B2B success. Expected to soon become a $412 billion industry, content marketing is cost effective to create while yielding high value. Not only is content marketing economical to produce, but it&#8217;s also an easy way to build brand awareness. &#8230; <a href="https://amandanicosia.com/5-tips-for-better-b2b-content-marketing/" class="more-link"><span>Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text">6 Tips for Better B2B Content Marketing</span></span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1037" class="elementor elementor-1037">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-13fe58c3 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="13fe58c3" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6da48ae5" data-id="6da48ae5" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-63b0ed3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="63b0ed3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							
<p>Content marketing is paving the way for B2B success. Expected to soon become a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.thedrum.com/news/2017/11/06/content-marketing-industry-be-worth-412bn-2021-following-four-year-growth-spurt" target="_blank">$412 billion industry</a>, content marketing is cost effective to create while yielding high value. </p>



<p>Not only is content marketing economical to produce, but it&#8217;s also an easy way to build brand awareness. If your audience can rely on you to solve their problems, they&#8217;ll be happy to select your brand when it&#8217;s time to make a purchase.</p>



<p>In this blog, we&#8217;ll review a list of content marketing basics to help you develop a consistent, seamless, B2B content strategy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Create Relationships</h2>



<p>Content marketing is foundational to any well-performing strategy. As we continue to create brand and customer equality, content marketing exists to further unify these relationships and speak for your brand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Consistency is Key</h2>



<p>Across industries, most B2B marketers employ some form of content marketing, but prioritizing consistency will produce valuable results. High-quality content marketing means creating campaigns, setting goals, and making schedules part of your regular routine. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Strategize and Organize</h2>



<p>A reliable strategy will help align your goals. Create content purposefully and be mindful of the narrative you want to tell. Build your content around core assets you&#8217;ve created for your target audience, attracting the right customers according to their own interests.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Make it Personal</h2>



<p>When creating, always keep your customers in mind. Highlight your product&#8217;s advantages that will help them solve a problem. Your customers want a personalized experience with your brand and rely on your knowledge to educate them.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Nurture is the Future</h2>



<p>Traditional marketing takes visitors through a qualification funnel, but if it’s only about the sale, the lowest always bidder wins. That&#8217;s why nurturing your leads through content marketing is essential, creating an ongoing relationship rather than an impersonal transaction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Spread the Word</h2>



<p>Through content promotion, B2B marketers are advised to follow the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.webpronews.com/neil-patel-content-marketing/" target="_blank">80/20 rule</a>: Create content 20% of the time and promote it 80% of the time. Share content on multiple channels, giving your thought leadership a chance to be seen by all of your followers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>As B2B content marketing expands, so will your strategies. After all, effective digital marketing depends on great content. Remember that quality and consistency are pertinent to content marketing success &#8212; and don&#8217;t be afraid to try new tactics.</p>



<p><a href="http://test.local/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reach out</a> if you have any questions.</p>
						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
